Harriet Whitney Frishmuth Papers
Harriet Whitney Frishmuth Papers
- Correspondence-subject files
  - Chrysler, Walter P., Jr., 1965-1973 (Box 16)
  - Clark, William Price, 1970 (Box 16)
  - Cloud, Maxine (Mrs. John K. Cloud), 1965-1972 (Box 16)
  - Collens, Charles 1940, 1949 (Box 16)
  - Columbus Museum of Arts and Crafts, Inc. Columbus, Georgia, 1969 (Box 16)
  - The Corcoran Gallery of Art, 1931 (Box 16)
  - Corn Products Refining Company, 1947-1948 (Box 16)
  - Council of American Artist Societies, Inc., 1966 (Box 16)
  - Craig, Frank R., 1935-1937 (Box 16)
  - Crane, Bruce, undated (Box 16)
  - Curran, Charles C., 1936 (Box 16)
  - Dallas Art Association, 1927 (Box 16)
  - Daly, Sue and Joe, 1972-1974 (Box 16)
  - Davey, Mildred, 1942; 1946,; undated (Box 16)
  - Dayton, Ruth Woods, 1961; 1965 (Box 16)
  - Delbos, Julian, undated (Box 16)
  - Deltiel, Desha and DeLue, Donald, 1963; 1966 (Box 16)
  - Dibrell Brothers, Inc, 1957 (Box 16)
  - Diehl, Isaac, 1951 (Box 16)
  - Dill, Colby and Elsie DeLamarter, 1929; 1930,; 1935,; undated (Box 17)
  - Dodd, Loring Holmes, 1933 (Box 17)
  - Drake, William J., 1945-1959 (Box 17)
  - Duco Color Advisory Service, 1927 (Box 17)
  - Emergency Relief Bureau City of New York, 1935 (Box 17)
  - Erkins Studios, Inc., 1953-1973; 4 folders (Box 17)
  - Estopinal, Albert, 1930 (Box 17)
  - Fairchild, F. Leslie, 1944 (Box 17)
  - Feldman, Sam, 1967; 1974,; 1978 (Box 17)
  - Festival of Arts Laguna Beach California, 1974; 1978-1979 (Box 17)
  - Findlay Galleries New York, 1969-1974 (Box 17)
  - Fine Arts Foundation, 1933-1934 (Box 17)
  - Flanagan, John, 1934 (Box 17)
  - Flint, William Russell, 1929 (Box 17)
  - The Florentine Craftsman, Inc., 1970 (Box 17)
  - Forest Lawn Memorial Parks and Mortuary, Glendale, California, 1966-1967 (Box 17)
  - Foshay, Wilbur B., 1926-1933 (Box 17)
  - Foster, Walter T., 1961-1962; 1974 (Box 17)
  - Fraley, Angela E., 1973-1975 (Box 17)
  - French, Daniel Chester, 1930 (Box 17)
  - Frisch, Victor, 1929 (Box 17)
  - Frishmuth, Louise B., undated (Box 18)
  - Fry, Homer l., 1949-1956 (Box 18)
  - The Gage Galleries Cleveland, Ohio, 1927 (Box 18)
  - The Garden Club of America, 1928-1931 (Box 18)
  - The Garden Magazine, 1923 (Box 18)
  - Gardiner, William Tudor, 1930 (Box 18)
  - Gartz, Gloria, 1969-1974 (Box 18)
  - Gaskill, C. W., 1930 (Box 18)
  - General Federation of Women’s Clubs, 1929 (Box 18)
  - Gerard, Elizabeth, 1969 (Box 18)
  - Glinsky, Vincent and Cleo Hartwig, 1973; 1975 (Box 18)
  - The Gorham Company Bronze Division, 1923-1945; 7 folders (Box 18)
  - The Gorham Company Bronze Division, 1946-1960; undated; 8 folders (Box 19)
  - James Graham & Sons, 1947-1959 (Box 19)
  - Grand Central Art Galleries, 1926-1939; 1940-1946,; 1964,1973; 2 folders (Box 19)
  - Grasso, Ella T., 1971 (Box 19)
  - Gregory, Julian A., 1965-1970 (Box 19)
  - The Grogan Company, 1947 (Box 19)
  - Grotas, Joseph, 1975 (Box 19)
  - Hall, Margaret D., 1975-1976 (Box 20)
  - Hamlin, Genevieve, undated (Box 20)
  - Hammaker, Frank Ensor, 1946-1954 (Box 20)
  - Hammaker, Paul, 1975 (Box 20)
  - Hammond, Irene Fenton, 1928-1929 (Box 20)
  - Hancock, Walker, 1935 (Box 20)
  - John Hanna, Incorporated, 1950-1955 (Box 20)
  - Harkness, Mary Stillman, 1935 (Box 20)
  - Hartley, Joan, 1931 (Box 20)
  - Hatcher, O. Latham, 1932 (Box 20)
  - Herman, Leonora Owsley, 1934 (Box 20)
  - The hermitage Foundation, 1951; 1970-1973 (Box 20)
  - Hirsch, Maurice, 1976-1977 (Box 20)
  - Hogan, Frank J., 1925 (Box 20)
  - Huntington, Anna Hyatt, 1966-1973 (Box 20)
  - Ingraham, Dudley S., 1969 (Box 20)
  - International Exhibition of Art and History Rome, Italy, 1911 (Box 20)
  - J. B. Hudson Company, 1947-1952; undated (Box 20)
  - J. H. Small and Sons, 1921-1931; 1938,; 1950 (Box 20)
  - James Whitcomb Riley Memorial Association, 1931-1932; undated (Box 20)
  - Janowsky, Bela, 1934 (Box 20)
  - The Joan of Arc Statue Committee of the City of New York, 1924-1925 (Box 20)
  - John Levy Galleries, Inc., 1951 (Box 20)
  - Johnson, Robert Underwood, 1914 (Box 20)
  - Jones, Francis Arthur, 1924; 1928,; 1934 (Box 20)
  - Keystone View Company, Inc., 1942 (Box 20)
  - Knickerbocker, Mrs. William H., 1938-1940 (Box 20)
  - Knowlton, Frederic K., 1927 (Box 20)
  - Knox, Henry D., 1931-1932 (Box 20)
  - Kroll, Leon, 1937 (Box 20)
  - Lampkin, Lucy, 1932-1934 (Box 20)
  - Lathrop, Gertrude, 1930 (Box 20)
  - Leonard, Arthur G., 1928 (Box 20)
  - Library of Congress Copyright Office, 1921 (Box 21)
  - The Lila Meade Valentine Memorial Association, 1928-1936 (Box 21)
  - The Little Gallery New York, 1931 (Box 21)
  - Liturgical Arts Society, Inc., 1941-1942 (Box 21)
  - Lober, Georg, undated (Box 21)
  - Look, 1969 (Box 21)
  - The Loring Andrews Company, 1947 (Box 21)
  - Luisi, Jerry, 1969-1973 (Box 21)
  - Lundquist, Louis, 1936 (Box 21)
  - MacLeary, Bonnie, 1930 (Box 21)
  - Maloof, Waleed, G., 1970; 1976-1977 (Box 21)
  - Mark of the Phoenix Gallery New York, 1966-1967 (Box 21)
  - Mason, Roy M., 1961 (Box 21)
  - Mayo Clinic, 1927 (Box 21)
  - McDonough, John J., 1968-1970 (Box 21)
  - Medallic Art Company, 1928-1929; 1948,; 1970 (Box 21)
  - Meier, Nellie S., 1930-1935 (Box 21)
  - Mercersburg Academy Mercersburg, Pennsylvania, 1931-1933 (Box 21)
  - Metropolitan Museum of Art New York, New York, 1926-1927; 1966-1970,; 1980 (Box 21)
  - The Milch Galleries, 1928 (Box 21)
  - Military Census and Inventory of 1917 State of New York (Box 21)
  - Milwaukee Art Institute, 1925 (Box 21)
  - Moll, Leo Zeimssen, 1931 (Box 21)
  - Morice, Mary H., 1930 (Box 21)
  - Morris, V. C., 1951 (Box 21)
  - Morton, Willie T., 1926-1928 (Box 21)
  - Mullen, John Kernan, 1926-1927 (Box 21)
  - The Municipal Art Society, 1930 (Box 21)
  - Murphree Memorial University of Florida, 1928 (Box 21)
  - Murray Hill Association, Inc., 1931 (Box 21)
  - National Academy of Design, 1914; 1923-1935,; 1965-1983,; undated (Box 21)
  - National Academy School of Fine Arts, 1967-1968; 1983-1984 (Box 22)
  - National Arts Club, 1924-1936; 1970-1973 (Box 22)
  - The National Education Association of the United States, 1933 (Box 22)
  - National Institute of Social Sciences, 1926-1928 (Box 22)
  - National Portrait Gallery, 1963-1972 (Box 22)
  - National Sculpture Society, 1913-1929 (Box 21)
  - National Sculpture Society, 1930-1933; 1934-1946,; 1948,; 1951-1957,; 1966,; 1971,; 1976,; 1979; undated; 3 folders (Box 22)
  - National Small Sculpture Committee, 1928-1930 (Box 22)
  - National Society of American Art, undated (Box 22)
  - National War Work Council of the YMCA, 1919 (Box 22)
  - Neilson, Raymond, 1926 (Box 22)
  - Nelson, Gary Boone, 1977-1979 (Box 22)
  - The New Britain Museum of American Art, 1970-1984 (Box 22)
  - New York Academy of Medicine Medal, 1930-1931 (Box 22)
  - New York University Hall of Fame, 1950-1951; 1956 (Box 22)
  - New York World’s Fair 1939, 1938-1940 (Box 22)
  - Newall, Joseph, 1940 (Box 22)
  - Newbold, Sara Glenwood, 1939 (Box 22)
  - Newman Galleries, 1965; 1970 (Box 22)
  - Nickerson, Ruth, 1978-1979 (Box 22)
  - The Norfolk Foundation, 1927; 1951-1952 (Box 22)
  - Norfolk Museum of Arts and Sciences, 1934-1935; 1966-1970 (Box 22)
  - O’Brien’s Art Emporium Scottsdale, Arizona, 1958-1967 (Box 22)
  - Oertel, C. W., 1930 (Box 22)
  - Olympic Games Los Angeles 1932 (Box 22)
  - Paige Detroit Motorcar Co., 1927 (Box 22)
  - The Park Gallery, 1931 (Box 22)
  - Peck, Maxine, 1950-1952 (Box 22)
  - Pen and Brush, Inc., 1948; 1967-1977 (Box 23)
  - Perrine, Alden J., 1959-1964 (Box 23)
  - Philbrook Art Center, 1962 (Box 23)
  - Phillips, Lee Eldas, 1975 (Box 23)
  - Platt, Eleanor, undated (Box 23)
  - Plummer, A. Newton, 1947 (Box 23)
  - Presby-Leland Studios, 1927-1930 (Box 23)
  - Presby-Leland Studios, 1931-1952; 2 folders (Box 23)
  - Pritchett, Margaret K., 1943 (Box 23)
  - Purdy, W. Frank, 1921; 1928 (Box 23)
  - Putnam, Brenda, 1921 (Box 23)
  - Quick, Armand J., 1928 (Box 23)
  - Rabbage, Lewis Hoyer, 1982 (Box 23)
  - Rawcliffe Foundry, 1953-1958 (Box 23)
  - Reitz, Edward R., 1928 (Box 23)
  - Reul, Alexander, 1927-1942; undated (Box 23)
  - Richard, Betti, 1972 (Box 23)
  - Roerich, Nicholas, 1930 (Box 23)
  - Roman Bronze Works, Inc., 1948-1973; 4 folders (Box 23)
  - Ross, Percy N., 1972 (Box 24)
  - Rubloff, Arthur, 1966-1978 (Box 24)
  - Ruskin, Sofia, 1939 (Box 24)
  - Sektberg, Willard, 1977 (Box 24)
  - Sesquicentennial Exposition Philadelphia, 1926 (Box 24)
  - Shabby Shoppe, Inc. Houston, Texas, 1947-1958 (Box 24)
  - Sirovich, William I., 1935 (Box 24)
  - Skoog, Karl F., 1929 (Box 24)
  - Sloane, Florence (Mrs. William), 1931; 1948-1951,; undated (Box 24)
  - Société Des Artiste Français, 1930 (Box 24)
  - The Society of Medalists, 1929-1939; 1971-1974,; undated (Box 24)
  - Squier, Socrates, 1825; 1826,; 1878,; undated (Box 24)
  - Stern, Loren J., 1977-1980 (Box 24)
  - Stillman, Charlotte, 1918 (Box 24)
  - Swiss Cottage studio, 1926; 1937-1951,; undated (Box 24)
  - Syracuse University, 1964-1971; 1974 (Box 24)
  - Taggart, Lucy, 1929-1934; undated (Box 24)
  - Talcott, Ruth, undated; childhood reminiscences (Box 24)
  - Talcott, Ruth, 1939; 1943,; undated; family history (Box 24)
  - Talcott, Ruth, 1942-1954; undated; Women’s Army Corps (Box 24)
  - Treasury Department Section of Painting and Sculpting, 1935 (Box 25)
  - Trent, D. Leonard, 1980 (Box 25)
  - United Galvano Art Company, 1938 (Box 25)
  - United States Trust Company of New York, 1939 (Box 25)
  - Vandersteel, William, 1975-1978 (Box 25)
  - Van Deventer, Robert P., 1961-1968; 1971 (Box 25)
  - Vandever, V. Vincent, 1956-1966 (Box 25)
  - The Virginia Museum of Fine Arts, 1935 (Box 25)
  - Wagel, Francine, 1940 (Box 25)
  - Walden, Eleanor B. and Madeline K., 1923-1928; 1946 (Box 25)
  - Ward, DeWitt, 1936 (Box 25)
  - Watson, Thomas J., undated (Box 25)
  - Weinman, Adolph Alexander, 1921; 1937 (Box 25)
  - Welling, Richard, 1937 (Box 25)
  - West Laurel Hill Cemetery Co. Bala-Cynwyd. Pennsylvania, 1936-1937 (Box 25)
  - James T. White & Company, 1926-1927 (Box 25)
  - Whittemore, Frances Davis, 1934 (Box 25)
  - W. A. Wilde Publishers, 1931 (Box 25)
  - Wilson, Edith Bolling, 1931-1935; undated; 2 folders (Box 25)
  - Winthrop, Emily, 1921 (Box 25)
  - W. H. Wise & Company, Inc., 1939 (Box 25)
  - Catherine Lorillard Wolfe Art Club, Inc., 1965-1980; 2 folders (Box 26)
  - Woman’s International Exposition Detroit, Michigan, 1929 (Box 26)
  - Zeier, John and Dorothy, 1946 (Box 26)
  - Zork, David, 1948 (Box 26)
- Financial and legal records
  - Copyright and Patent certificates, 1910-1927 (Box 26)
  - Gorham Company transactions, 1935-1941 (Box 26)
  - Passports, 1937; 1951,; 1955,; 1961 (Box 26)
  - Sculpture orders ledger, 1917-1948 (Box 27)
  - Sculpture sold, 1910-1951 (Box 26)
  - Sculpture sold ledger, 1958-1991 (Box 26)
  - Social Security card, 1950 (Box 26)
  - Student accounts notebook, undated (Box 26)
  - Tax documents, 1935-1937 (Box 26)
- Memorabilia
  - Artwork by others
    - Caricature of Harriet Frishmuth by Matias Santoyo, undated (Box 27)
  - Awards and certificates
    - Allied Artists of America, Inc. 13th Annual Exhibition Medal, 1925 (Box 28)
    - Catherine Lorillard Wolfe Art Club Medal for Sculpture, 1922 (Box 28)
    - Elizabeth Watrous Medal for Sculpture, undated (Box 28)
    - Festival of Arts Lifetime Membership, undated (Box 28)
    - National Academy of Design, 1926; 1929 (Oversize 9)
    - National Sculpture Society Fellow, 1958 (Oversize 10)
    - National Sculpture Society medal, undated (Box 28)
    - Pan-Pacific International Exposition Honorable Mention, 1915 (Oversize 10)
    - Miscellaneous certificates, 1927; 1963,; 1972,; 1975 (Box 28)
  - Catalogs
    - Catherine Lorillard Wolfe Art Club, 1966 (Box 29)
    - Christie’s, 1981-1984; 5 folders (Box 29)
    - Grand Central Art Galleries, 1928 (Box 29)
    - Phillips, 1982 (Box 29)
    - Sloan’s, 1983 (Box 29)
    - Schwartz, 1971 (Box 29)
    - Sotheby’s, 1982 (Box 29)
  - Clippings
    - Miscellaneous, 1922; 1936-1969; 2 folders (Box 29)
    - Miscellaneous, 1970-1984; 2 folders (Box 30)
  - Photographs
    - Adirondacks, New Haven, Provincetown, undated (Box 30)
    - Barte, Leon, undated (Box 30)
    - Bermuda, Gaspe, undated (Box 30)
    - Deltiel, Desha, undated (Box 30)
    - Deltiel, Desha and Leja, 1962 (Box 30)
    - Deltiel, Desha, Jean and Leon Barte, undated (Box 30)
    - Europe, 1955 (Box 30)
    - France, 1955; undated; 5 folders (Box 30)
    - Frishmuth, Harriet, undated; 2 folders (Box 30)
    - Frishmuth, Harriet, undated (Box 31)
    - Frishmuth family, undated (Box 31)
    - Gorham Factory, undated (Box 31)
    - Heritage Village, undated (Box 31)
    - Knox Estate, 1927 (Box 31)
    - Langeloth Estate, undated (Box 31)
    - Metropolitan Museum of Art Christmas, undated (Box 31)
    - Muray, Nikolas and Leya, undated (Box 31)
    - North Cape cruise, Ireland, Belgium, undated (Box 31)
    - Sculpture by others, undated (Box 31)
    - Silvermine Avenue house and garden, 1956 (Box 31)
    - Swiss Cottage, 1959; 1964,; undated (Box 31)
    - Switzerland, 1955 (Box 31)
    - Talcott, Ruth, undated (Box 31)
    - Unveiling of Scherzo for the Foshay Tower, undated (Box 31)
    - Vacation cruise to Caracas, 1964 (Box 31)
    - Vacations Philadelphia, Mystic, 1958 (Box 31)
    - Vacations Washington, Canada, Vermont, 1956 (Box 31)
    - Valentine, Lila Meade, undated (Box 31)
    - World’s Fair, Frishmuth’s The Vine, 1964 (Box 31)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 31)
    - Miscellaneous 1942, undated (Box 31)
    - Miscellaneous glass plate negatives, undated (Box 32)
  - Postcards
    - Alaska, 1945 (Box 33)
    - St Bertrand-De-Comminges, undated (Box 33)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 33)
  - Printed material
    - Festival of Arts and Pageant of the Masters, 1964; 1965,; 1976 (Box 33)
    - Heritage Villager, 1970; 1971,; 1974,; 1977 (Box 33)
    - National Sculpture Society, 1968 -1969; 1980 (Box 33)
    - Valeria House Oscawana, New York, undated (Box 33)
    - Miscellaneous, 1917-1919; 1964,; 1966,; 1971,; 1973,; undated (Box 33)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Oversize 5)
  - Scrapbooks
    - Scrapbook, 1924-1928; 2 folders (Box 33)
    - Scrapbook, 1928-1936 (Box 34)
    - Sculpture, 1910-1928; 2 folders (Box 34)
    - Sculpture, 1911-1924 (Oversize 4)
    - Sculpture, undated (Oversize 7)
    - Sculpture, undated (Oversize 9)
    - Talcott, Ruth W.A.A.C. Training Center, 1942 (Oversize 10)
    - Talcott Family History, undated (Oversize 5)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Address cards, undated (Box 34)
    - Brass plate from 6 Sniffen Road Harriet Frishmuth Studio, undated (Box 35)
    - Crest of the Waves theft from Foster Art Service office, 1974 (Box 35)
    - Eiffel Tower souvenir medal, undated (Box 35)
    - Fortune telling cards, undated (Box 35)
    - Map of Paris, undated (Box 35)
    - National Sculpture Society Fiftieth Anniversary Medal, 1943 (Box 35)
    - Red Cross insignia, 1918 (Box 35)
    - The Seventh Sister by Edward E. Reitz, undated (Box 35)
    - Sketch of setting for Frishmuth statue, undated (Oversize 9)
    - Talcott, Ruth diary, 1962 (Box 35)
- Writings
  - Vacation diary, 1935 (Box 35)
  - Vacation diary, 1965 (Box 35)
  - Why a Sundial Shows Us the Correct Time, undated (Box 35)